Guide to the Central Washington University Office of the President, Administrative Records 1979-2002
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Office of the President, Administrative Records
1979-2002
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG014-05-65
Central Washington University. Office of the President
5.25 cubic feet 10 letter sized document cases and 1 half letter sized document case Types in good condition
The collection consists of strategic reports, salary equity surveys, educational exchange and consortium agreements, and correspondences created or received by the Office of the President at Central Washington University from 1979 to 2002.
Historical Note
The Office of the President at Central Washington University originated with the appointment of a Principal for Washington State Normal School by the Board of Trustees in the fall of 1891. The title of Principal was changed to President in 1914 and continues in use today.
Along with other records, this collection contains planning notes, budget requests, reorganization reports, and educational agreement contracts from the departments of Academic Affairs, International Programs, Strategic Planning, and University Centers at Central Washington University.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Alphabetical by subject title of file and chronological within file.
Open to the public for educational research.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Central Washington University. Office of the President
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History; Washington (State)--History
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
College administrators
- Ad Hoc Dispute Resolution Committee, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Academic Affairs - Academic Affairs Council, 2000 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Academic Affairs - Airway Science Grant Agreement, 1992 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Arts, 1999 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Asia Pacific Studies, 2001 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of English, 2001 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of History, 1985-2001 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Music, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Music/Chamber Music Residency, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Music/Panerio's Te Deum Copyright, 1992 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Philosophy, 1998 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Theatre Arts, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Academic Affairs - College of Arts and Humanities/Department of Theatre Arts/Laughing Horse Summer Theatre, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Academic Affairs - College of Business/AACSB Accreditation, 2001 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Academic Affairs - College of Education and Professional Studies/Family and Consumer Science Department, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Academic Affairs - College of Education and Professional Studies/Industrial and Engineering Technology, 1987-2001 (Box-folder 1-16)
- Academic Affairs - College of Education and Professional Studies/Industrial and Engineering Technology/Center for Applied Science and Engineering Technology, 1984 (Box-folder 1-17)
- Academic Affairs - College of Education and Professional Studies/Teacher Education Programs, 2000 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Academic Affairs - College of Education and Professional Studies/Teaching and Learning Program, 2001 (Box-folder 1-19)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Geological Sciences, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 1-20)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Geological Sciences/Lind Hall, 2000 (Box-folder 1-21)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Law and Justice, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 1-22)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Mathematics, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 1-23)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Physics, 2001 (Box-folder 1-24)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Political Science, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 1-25)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Psychology, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 1-26)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Psychology/Chimpanzee and Human Communications Institute, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 1-27)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Psychology/Masters Degree Organizational Development, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 1-28)
- Academic Affairs - College of the Sciences/Department of Psychology/Primate Research Facility Groundbreaking, 1990 (Box-folder 1-29)
- Academic Affairs - Ronald E. McNair Program, 2001 (Box-folder 1-30)
- Academic Affairs - School of Business/Business Administration, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 1-31)
- Academic Affairs - School of Business and Economics, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 1-32)
- Academic Affairs - School of Business/Economics, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 1-33)
- Academic Affairs - Office of Continuing Education/Cornerstone Programs, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 1-34)
- Academic Affairs - Office of Continuing Education/Graduate Studies, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 1-35)
- Academic Affairs - Office of Continuing Education/Title III (Box-folder 1-36)
- Academic Affairs - Office of Graduate Studies and Research/Graduate Council, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 1-37)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/Administrative Officers, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/Class Size Policy, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/Department of Biology, 1999 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/General Education Program, 1996 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/Medical Technology Program, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 2-5)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/Phase II Planning, 1997 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/Program Plans, 2000 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Academic Affairs - Office of the Provost/University Space Notes, 1997 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Administration / Academic Support Systems Project, 2000 (Box-folder 2-9)
- Administration / American with Disabilities Act Affairs, 1994 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Administration / Bill Massy Forum, 2000 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Administration - Budget/Administrative Restructuring, 2000 (Box-folder 2-12)
- Administration - Budget/Advisory Committee Meeting Notes, 2002 (Box-folder 2-13)
- Administration - Budget/Cuts, 2001 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Administration - Budget/Enrollment Issues, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 2-15)
- Administration - Budget/Exempt Salary Increases, 2001 (Box-folder 2-16)
- Administration - Budget/Exempt Salary Plan/CUPA, 1995 (Box-folder 2-17)
- Administration - Budget/Government Relations, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 2-18)
- Administration - Budget/Office Reorganization, 2001 (Box-folder 2-19)
- Administration - Budget/Operating Budget Request, 2000 (Box-folder 2-20)
- Administration - Budget/Performance Based Budgeting, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 2-21)
- Administration - Budget/Potential Budget Cuts, 2001 (Box-folder 2-22)
- Administration - Budget/Process, 2001 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Administration - Budget/Budget Request Presentation/Higher Education Coordinating Board, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 2-24)
- Administration - Budget/Budget Request Presentation/Higher Education Coordinating Board/Operating Budget, 2000 (Box-folder 2-25)
- Administration - Budget/Budget Reorganization Reports/Administrative Structure Committee, 2000 (Box-folder 2-26)
- Administration - Dolph Norton Clippings, 1999 (Box-folder 2-27)
- Administration - Educational Opportunity Center, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 2-28)
- Administration - Ellensburg School District/Central Washington University Proclamation, 1996 (Box-folder 2-29)
- Administration - Enrollment, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 2-30)
- Administration - Enrollment Management and Marketing, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Administration - Enrollment Recovery, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Administration - Enrollment and Retention, 2000 (Box-folder 3-3)
- Administration - Executive Orders, 2000 (Box-folder 3-4)
- Administration - Home Page Memorandum, 1995 (Box-folder 3-5)
- Administration - Institutional Assessment Reports, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 3-6)
- Administration - Legislature, 2001 (Box-folder 3-7)
- Administration - National Prayer and Observance Speech, 2001 (Box-folder 3-8)
- Administration - Performance Measure, 1997 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Administration - Provost Search, 2001 (Box-folder 3-10)
- Administration - Puget Power Transmission Lines Report, 1996 (Box-folder 3-11)
- Administration - Reorganization Documents, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 3-12)
- Administration - Self Support Programs, 1993 (Box-folder 3-13)
- Administration - State of the University, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3-14)
- Campus Climate - Reports, 1998 (Box-folder 3-15)
- Campus Climate - Task Force Reports, 1998 (Box-folder 3-16)
- Campus Master Plan - Committee Notes, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 3-17)
- Commencement/ Events, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 3-18)
- Committee on Salary Equity, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 3-19)
- Community Building Program, 2001 (Box-folder 3-20)
- Correspondences - Affirmative Action, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 3-21)
- Correspondences - Department of Agriculture/Empowerment Zone Program, 1998 (Box-folder 3-22)
- Correspondences - Department of Education/Educational Opportunity Center, 2001 (Box-folder 3-23)
- Correspondences - Faculty Letters, 2001 (Box-folder 3-24)
- Correspondences - Faculty Letters/Connie Roberts, 2001 (Box-folder 3-25)
- Correspondences - General Correspondences/A - C, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 3-26)
- Correspondences - General Correspondences/D - M, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 3-27)
- Correspondences - Professor of the Year Letters, 2001 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Correspondences - Reference/Personal Letters, 2000 (Box-folder 4-2)
- Department of Athletics - Athletic Director, 2000 (Box-folder 4-3)
- Department of Athletics - Correspondences, 2001 (Box-folder 4-4)
- Department of Athletics - Herb Dempsey/Title IV Issues, 1999 (Box-folder 4-5)
- Department of Athletics - PacWest Issues, 2000 (Box-folder 4-6)
- Department of Athletics - Student Athlete Contract, 1999 (Box-folder 4-7)
- Department of Athletics - Statistics, 2000 (Box-folder 4-8)
- Diversity Council, 2001 (Box-folder 4-9)
- Faculty Forum Notes, 1998 (Box-folder 4-10)
- Faculty Grievance Committee Correspondence, 2001 (Box-folder 4-11)
- Faculty Salaries - Adjustment Reports, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 4-12)
- Faculty Salaries - Attorney General Opinion, 1998 (Box-folder 4-13)
- Foundation and Development - Agreement and By Laws, 2001 (Box-folder 4-14)
- Foundation and Development - Development, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 4-15)
- Foundation and Development - Governor Booth Gardner Letter, 1998 (Box-folder 4-16)
- Foundation and Development - Major Donors, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 4-17)
- Foundation and Development - O'Shaughnessy Campaign, 1999 (Box-folder 4-18)
- Foundation and Development - Yakima Federal Savings and Loan Association Letters, 1999 (Box-folder 4-19)
- General Education Committee Meeting Notes, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 4-20)
- Geographical Information Systems - Executive Summary Correspondences, 1987 (Box-folder 4-21)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 4-22)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 5-1)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5-2)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 5-3)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 5-4)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 5-5)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 5-6)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 5-7)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 5-8)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5-9)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 6-1)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 6-2)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 6-3)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 6-4)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 6-5)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 7-1)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 7-2)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 7-3)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7-4)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 7-5)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7-6)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 7-7)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 7-8)
- Graduate Council Meeting Minutes, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 7-9)
- Government Relations - Central Washington University Building for the Future Proclamation, 1998 (Box-folder 7-10)
- Government Relations - Ellensburg, City of, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 7-11)
- Government Relations - Ellensburg, City of/Central Washington University Natural Gas Contact, 2000 (Box-folder 7-12)
- Government Relations - Initiative 200, 1999 (Box-folder 7-13)
- Government Relations - KYVE/Central Washington University Agreement, 2000 (Box-folder 7-14)
- Government Relations - Legislature Issues, 2001 (Box-folder 7-15)
- Government Relations - Tang Ranch, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7-16)
- Government Relations - Washington Executive Ethics Board/Use of State Resources Report, 2001 (Box-folder 7-17)
- Government Relations - Washington State Arts Commission/Central Washington University Art Collection Inventory, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 7-18)
- Government Relations - Washington State Education Foundation, 2000 (Box-folder 7-19)
- Human Subjects Research Committee Notes, 2000 (Box-folder 7-20)
- Intercollegiate Nursing Education Center, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 8-1)
- Interinstitutional Committee of Academic Officers Record of Actions Taken, 2000 (Box-folder 8-2)
- International Programs, 2001 (Box-folder 8-3)
- International Programs - Agreements, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 8-4)
- International Programs - Anhui University, 1980-2001 (Box-folder 8-5)
- International Programs - Anhui University China, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 8-6)
- International Programs - Asia University, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 8-7)
- International Programs - Chili Trip, 1997 (Box-folder 8-8)
- International Programs - China Program, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 8-9)
- International Programs - China Trip, 1996 (Box-folder 8-10)
- International Programs - Correspondences, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 8-11)
- International Programs - Fukuoka Jo, Gaikuin University, 2001 (Box-folder 8-12)
- International Programs - Ghana Trip, 1997 (Box-folder 8-13)
- International Programs - Gift Records, 1995 (Box-folder 8-14)
- International Programs - Gunma Prefectural Women's College, 1999 (Box-folder 8-15)
- International Programs - Hankyong National University, 2001 (Box-folder 8-16)
- International Programs - Holy Savior High School Taiwan, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 8-17)
- International Programs - International Studies, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 8-18)
- International Programs - Korea, 2001 (Box-folder 8-19)
- International Programs - Korea Pukyong National University, 1998 (Box-folder 8-20)
- International Programs - Kyoto University of Foreign Studies, 1997 (Box-folder 8-21)
- International Programs - Mexico Program, 1997 (Box-folder 8-22)
- International Programs - Moraga/Peoples Republic of China, 1999 (Box-folder 8-23)
- International Programs - Northern Jiaotong University, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 8-24)
- International Programs - Peoples Republic of China/Ministry of Land and Resources, 1999 (Box-folder 8-25)
- International Programs - Poland Exchange Program, 1998 (Box-folder 8-26)
- International Programs - Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, 1989 (Box-folder 8-27)
- International Programs - Republic of Korea, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 8-28)
- International Programs -Sanda City, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 8-29)
- International Programs - Shimane International College, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 8-30)
- International Programs - Shimane Prefectural Women's College, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 8-31)
- International Programs - Shimane University, 1982-2001 (Box-folder 8-32)
- International Programs - Shimane University/President Ichiro Yamada, 1995 (Box-folder 8-33)
- International Programs - Takushoku University, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 8-34)
- International Programs - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1987-2001 (Box-folder 8-35)
- International Programs - Universidad Austral De Chile, 1991 (Box-folder 8-36)
- International Programs - Universidad de La Coruna, 2000 (Box-folder 8-37)
- International Programs - Universidad de Valparaiso Chili, 1997 (Box-folder 8-38)
- KYVE Partnership, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 9-1)
- Library and Information Technology / Journal Cancellation Issue, 2000 (Box-folder 9-2)
- Library and Information Technology / Library Faculty Category and Salary Scale, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 9-3)
- Library and Information Technology - Sid Morrison Deed Gift and Agreement Materials Collection, 1992 (Box-folder 9-4)
- Marketing Group Meeting Notes, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9-5)
- Master Plan Committee Notes, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9-6)
- Master Plan Committee Notes, 1998 (Box-folder 9-7)
- North Snohomish, Island, Skagit Counties Higher Education Consortium/Notes, 2000 (Box-folder 9-8)
- North Snohomish, Island, Skagit Counties Higher Education Consortium/Everett Transit Station Lease, 2000 (Box-folder 9-9)
- North Snohomish, Island, Skagit Counties Higher Education Consortium/Operation and Meeting Notes, 2001 (Box-folder 9-10)
- News Articles and Media - Miscellaneous Articles, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 9-11)
- News Articles and Media - Athletics, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 9-12)
- News Articles and Media - Office of Residential Services, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9-13)
- Presidential Search Committee Correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 9-14)
- People of Color Participation and Diversity, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 9-15)
- Strategic Planning - Mission and Goals Statement, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 9-16)
- Strategic Planning - Strategic Planning Instruction Packet, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 9-17)
- Strategic Planning - Strategic Planning Synthesizing Committee/Notes, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 9-18)
- Strategic Planning - Strategic Planning Committee Notes, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 9-19)
- Strategic Planning - Strategic Planning Synthesizing Committee Planning Notes, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 9-20)
- Students - Sarah Shumate, 1997 (Box-folder 10-1)
- Students - The Students, 1995 (Box-folder 10-2)
- Students - Student Affairs, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 10-3)
- Students - Student Affairs/Campus Life, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 10-4)
- Students - Student Affairs/Diversity Issues, 2000 (Box-folder 10-5)
- Schools - ICAO Meeting Notes, 1991 (Box-folder 10-6)
- Schools - Partnership for Rural Improvement, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 10-7)
- Schools - University of Washington/Cooperative Agreement, 1992 (Box-folder 10-8)
- Schools - Western Washington University/Interagency Agreement, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 10-9)
- Schools - Western Washington University/Washington Campus Compact, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 10-10)
- Schools - Yakima Valley College/Heritage College/Interinstitutional Agreement, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 10-11)
- Schools - Yakima Valley Opportunities Industrialization Center/Educational Training Agreement, 1993 (Box-folder 10-12)
- University Centers - Briefing/Central Washington University Degree Centers, 1995 (Box-folder 10-13)
- University Centers - Central Washington University/Edmonds Community College, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 10-14)
- University Centers - Central Washington University/Highline Community (Box-folder 10-15)
- University Centers - Correspondences, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 10-16)
- University Centers - Discussions, 2000 (Box-folder 10-17)
- University Centers - Facilities, 2000 (Box-folder 10-18)
- University Centers - Fort Lewis/Central Washington University, 1997 (Box-folder 10-19)
- University Centers - Fort Steilacoom Program, 1984-1999 (Box-folder 10-20)
- University Centers - Highline Community College/Central Washington University Collaboration, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 10-21)
- University Centers - History/Branch Campus, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 10-22)
- University Centers - Inventory, 2000 (Box-folder 10-23)
- University Centers - Joint Facility/Central Washington University/Yakima Valley College Groundbreaking, 2001 (Box-folder 10-24)
- University Centers - Letters of Support/Central Washington University/Highline Community College Higher Education Building, 2000 (Box-folder 10-25)
- University Centers - Lynnwood Center/Edmonds Community College Prospectus, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 10-26)
- University Centers - North Snohomish, Island, Skagit Counties Higher Education Consortium, 1999 (Box-folder 10-27)
- University Centers - Notes, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 10-28)
- University Centers - Pierce College, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 10-29)
- University Centers - SeaTac Center, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 10-30)
- University Centers - Transition Agreement/Admissions/Procedures for Business Students, 1989 (Box-folder 10-31)
- University Centers - Wenatchee Center, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 10-32)
- University Centers - Wenatchee Valley College/Extended University Program, 1996 (Box-folder 10-33)
- University Centers - Yakima Basin Center, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 10-34)
- University Centers - Yakima Center, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 11-1)
- University Centers - Yakima Valley College/Central Washington (Box-folder 11-2)
- University Collaboration, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 11-3)
- University Centers - Yakima Valley College Programs, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 11-4)
- University Centers - Yakima Valley Higher Education, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 11-5)
- University Computing Committee, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 11-6)
- University Forum Correspondences, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 11-7)
- University Forum Notes, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 11-8)
- University Marketing Committee, 1998 (Box-folder 11-9)
- Washington Higher Education Telecommunications Systems, 1993 (Box-folder 11-10)
- Washington Higher Education Network, 1995 (Box-folder 11-11)